### **CARLOS JARA**

cjjara002@gmail.com | carlosjaraportfolio.com |linkedin.com/in/carlos-j-jara | 424-295-9452

### **SUMMARY**

Developer with experience in React, Redux, Hooks, JavaScript ES6, as well as backend services, such as AWS, MuleSoft, SQL and C#. Additional experience in backend tooling, Swagger and Postman, and experience in cloud hosting tools, such as Netlify.

#### SKILLS

Front End: React JS, Redux, Hooks, jQUERY, JavaScript ES6, CSS3, Bootstrap 4, AXIOS, HTML, Yarn

Web Service: C#, .Net Core, ADO.Net, .Net, MuleSoft

Back End: T-SQL, SQL Server

Back End Tooling: Swagger, Postman

**Cloud Hosting Tools:** Netlify

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Application Developer I** | CO-OP Financial Services

August 2021- April 2022

- Developed a microservice using .NET Core connecting client and server-side resources to save business resources and cost, to support and streamline business operations, while providing added security to the end user.
- Connected the front-end to the web server using Axios to make API calls.
- Presented new features to developers, product managers, and QA team.
- Identified and resolved problems uncovered by testing, automated, and feedback.
- Used Postman and Swagger to test applications.
- Built complex transformations using DataWeave in Anypoint Studio.
- Enhanced, troubleshot, and maintained existing applications in MuleSoft.
- Engaged in the development of MuleSoft service endpoints using Anypoint Platform to reverse a credit card transaction and repost as a loan.
- •Built out custom components on the front end using React, Hooks, and Redux.

# Web Developer | Cleaning.Unique

January 2020 – August 2021

- Created secure RESTful API services connecting client and server-side resources.
- Implemented SQL Server stored procedures to be executed using ADO.Net from the web service.
- Wrote SQL Stored Procedures using SQL Server Management Studio (SMSS) for all standard CRUD operations called from the web server/C#.
- Converted designs/prototypes into pixel-perfect, fully functioning and maintainable code for various devices and platforms using CSS and Bootstrap.
- Used Redux for state management and React JS to produce custom components.
- Sent and retrieved data from the web server through API calls using Axios on the front-end and ADO.Net on the web server.

### **EDUCATION**

Sabio | Web Development, Computer Science 2019

University of California, Riverside | Bachelor of Science, Anthropology 2012-2016